# **SCOTT NEWCOMB**

804-307-1145 sconewcomb@gmail.com www.sconewcomb.com

Front End Web Developent, Email Design/Development, Custom WP Themes, Responsive Development, iPhone Application Development, MVC, Object Oriented Development, Testing/Debugging, Client Relations

## **SUMMARY**

To obtain a creative and challenging position that enables me to expand upon the web development and programming skills I've gained over the past six years. Most recently my path has led me to email design and development. With these newly discovered skills I have been able to build upon my generalist skill set. I want to continue incorporating this knowledge to learn and understand new technologies for producing a better user experience for the client.

### TECHNICAL SKILLS

HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, JSON, Photoshop, Dreamweaver, PHP, Objective-C, JAVA, Bootstrap, WordPress, Magento, Xcode, Eclipse, Komodo, Aptana, Code Igniter, GIT, Subversion, Postman, Microsoft Office, Mac/Window/Linux

## **EMPLOYMENT HISTORY**

# Aquent (Contracting with Capital One) | Richmond, VA

Front End Developer/Designer

May 2015-Present

- Recode and redesign emails to current brand standards
- Migrate emails to internal platform for automated send through new ESP
- Develop new ways to use APIs for special scripting utilized in emails
- Diagnose issues related to email entry, appearance and scripting errors
- Subject matter expert for new internal platform

# V4 Development | Richmond, VA

**Ir Developer** 

October 2011-April 2014

- Developed WordPress sites to client specifications
- Developed code for iPhone/iPad apps and placed in App Store
- Updated older sites with newer and better functionality
- Taught clients to use their new sites
- Used Photoshop to create various needed elements

# PoshTots | Richmond, VA

Merchandiser

June 2010-March 2013

- Edited images and loaded products to site
- Responsible for setting up product attributes in order to be transferred to new Magento platform
- Assisted in setting up new computers on network and repairing old computers

### CERTIFICATIONS

**EDUCATION** 

Network +, 2010 Security+, 2011

ECPI College of Technology, Richmond, VA BS in Information Technology, Network Security 2010, 3.78 GPA Graduated Spring 2010